Christopher Zeuch

QA Engineer ← in ► South Africa, He/Him
christopherzeuch.streamlit.app

About

I'm a hardworking and highly autonomous individual with deep passion for Quality Assurance and Engineering \red

I've worked for various companies and startups; with products ranging from PoCs and MVPs to large production systems in fintech and financial forecasting

I can work solo or as part of a team, both are enjoyable. I've also had the privilege of leading a small QA team that worked on various start-ups, where I gained experience in leading and mentoring >>

Having spent the last few years working exclusively with startups; my go-to "style" is lean and lightweight, enabling me to adjust test strategies as the business grows #

Work Experience

2023 - 2024

Founding QA Engineer at Kohort South Africa - Remote

This was my first opportunity to work as a solo, Founding QA Engineer. My main responsibility was to test all incoming Web App changes from the Platform team.

This meant building, implementing and integrating a testing process that was lean and lightweight, but robust enough to expand as the business grew.

During my time here I implemented an automated scripting strategy using SeleniumBase and a Streamlit app that generated testing datasets.

I also built a Streamlit app for my SeleniumBase scripts where I could spin up and tear down product functionality in any of our environments. This was later improved and productionized as part of a team hackathon.

Reason for leaving: Retrenchment

2021 - 2023

Lead QA Engineer at The Delta South Africa - Remote

At The Delta I grew from a Senior QA Engineer to a Lead QA Engineer.

Upon joining I started working for two Startups, one of which was <u>Precium</u>. Depending on the needs of the business I sometimes worked on other startups for short periods.

During this time I was responsible for leading and managing a small team of 3 QA Engineers of varying experience while they worked on their assigned projects.

Reason for leaving: Had the opportunity to work for Kohort

2016 - 2021

QA Engineer at Entersekt

Stellenbosch

At Entersekt I grew from a Junior QA Engineer to a Senior QA Engineer, working with almost all of the internal teams.

I first started in the SDK and Mobile Apps team where I was responsible for planning & executing feature testing, integrating testing & regression cycles.

I then moved to our Backend team, responsible for deploying and maintaining our backend systems on physical hardware appliances.

I then moved to our Platform team where I was responsible for organising & co-ordinating large-scale regressions across the organisation. During this time I also worked closely with the DevOps team as a scrum master.

Reason for leaving: Had the opportunity to work in the Startup space

2015 - 2016

Junior SQA Analyst at DVT Cape Town

At DVT I learned the fundamentals of Quality Assurance by working on three client projects:

- Mobile application on Android & iOS
- · Power BI project
- Educational game on Windows

After working on these client projects, I was contracted out to Entersekt where I worked directly with an engineering team for the first time.

Reason for leaving: Enterkset contract turned into fulltime employment

Side Projects

2024

My Profile | Streamlit at Personal

A simple Streamlit app that displays my professional profile, current tech stack, work experience, technical experience and side projects.

2024

♠ AFK Journey | Streamlit at Personal A Streamlit app that contains the questions and answers for the AFK Journey Trivia Quiz.

Users can do the following to get the answer:

Users can type the question (minimum of two words) and click the submit button to get an answer.

Alternatively, users can scroll through the True or False tables to find their question.

A collection of apps that I built to become familiar with Streamlit.

Writing

2023 Using YAGNI and testing context to simplify your testing

process, Kohort

I wote a blog post about my experience of implementing and improving my testing process at Kohort, which the

company offered to publish on their blog 🧡